A Guide to the Henry Luce Foundation records, American Art Program FA1854
Rockefeller Archive Center
Henry Luce Foundation records, American Art Program (Accession 2022:036)
1982-2019
Rockefeller Archive Center
Henry Luce Foundation
FA1854
3.23 Cubic Feet 9 containers: 8 letter document boxes, 1 half letter document box
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research.
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
The Henry Luce Foundation records, American Art Program record group contains information about the foundation's American Art program during the years 1982-2019. The files contain program and grant evaluations, advisor records, and dissertation research awards.
Art, American
- Luce Fund for Scholarships in American Art (LFSAA) Advisors, 1982-2012; 1
  - Past Advisors and Possibilities, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Evaluation Memos, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - William Homer, 1982-2012 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Carter Ratcliff, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Calvin Tomkins, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Luce Fund in American Art (LFAA) Advisors, 1987-2016; 2
  - Michael Brenson, 2009-2016 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Barbara Novak, 2003-2010 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Peter Plagens, 1987-2016 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Brenda Richardson, 1990-2016 (Box 2, Folder 11-13)
  - Kevin Stayton, 1998-2015 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
- Whitney Award, 2011-2012 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Luce Centers, 1984-2009 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- American Collections Enhancement (ACE) Initiative, 1995-2000 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Curatorial Sabbatical Exchange Initiative, 2000-2002 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- American Art Program Conservation Initiative, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- American Art Renewal Fund (AARF), 2010-2012 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- AAMD/American Art Survey, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- American Art Program Evaluation, Volume 1, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- American Art Program Evaluation, Volume 2, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
- American Art Program Evaluation, 2008-2013 (Box 4, Folder 26-27)
- American Art Program Evaluation - Background and Prep, 1993-2008 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- American Art Program Evaluation - Board Presentation and Follow-up, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- American Art Program Evaluation - Process, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- American Art Program Evaluation - Report, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- American Art Program Evaluation - TCC Group, 2007-2009 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Nelson-Atkins Museum of Art - American Paintings Collection, 1997-2007 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Philadelphia Museum of Art - American Silver and Metals Collection, 1983-2007 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Dissertation Research Awards, 1986-2019; 3
  - American Art Dissertation Research Awards - General Information, 2000-2005 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - American Art Dissertation Research Awards, 1996-2000; 2015 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Boston University, 1986-2014 (Box 5, Folder 37-38)
  - Columbia University, 1986-2006 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Cornell University, 1997-2015 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - CUNY Graduate Center, 1986-2014 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Emory University, 1999-2019 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Indiana University, 1994-2015 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1999-2015 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Northwestern University, 1997-2015 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Princeton University, 1998-2015 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Rutgers University, 1999-2015 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Stanford University, 1986-2015 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - University of California, Berkeley, 1998-2012 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, 1996-2018 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - University of California, Santa Barbara, 1999-2009 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - University of Delaware, 1986-2005 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - University of Iowa, 1997-2014 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - University of Kansas, 1988-2014 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - University of Maryland, 1997-2014 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - University of Michigan, 1986-2014 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - University of New Mexico, 1996-2015 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, 1998-2015 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1996-2007 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1998-2013 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - University of Rochester, 1999-2015 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - University of Southern California, 1999-2014 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - University of Texas, Austin, 1995-2014 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - University of Virginia, 1998-2014 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - University of Washington, 1997-2015 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Washington University at St. Louis, 1998-2019 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Yale University, 1986-2015 (Box 9, Folder 67-68)